A Guide to the Lewis A. Hall Papers, 1921-1977
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Lewis A. Hall Papers, 1921-1977
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1983-009
0.5 Cubic Feet 1 box
Papers of Lewis A. Hall, a 1924 graduate of Virginia Tech, consisting largely of memorabilia from his time at the university and as an active alumnus. Includes programs, certificates, textiles, and photographs, as well as drawings for engineering class assignments.
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Lewis A. Hall Papers were acquired by Special Collections prior to 1984.
Scope and Content
This collection contains papers of Lewis A. Hall, a 1924 graduate of Virginia Polytechnic Institute, and consists largely of university-related material from Hall's years as a student and honors awarded him as an alumnus. The collection contains several small textiles, including pennants, cadet chevrons, and Class of 1924 armbands. Also within the collection are programs, invitations, and other memorabilia from various athletic events and dances. (Included among these are a schedule and program for the Virginia Tech Minstrels.) Also contained in the collection are approximately 100 photographs, including Hall's studio portrait and group photos of the Cotillion Club of 1922/1923 and the 1924 freshman basketball team. Snapshots include views of "rat parades," football games, a snowball fight, and various campus views and unidentified students, as well as scenes from Reserve Officers' Training Corps camp at Fort Monroe, Virginia. A set of Hall's drawings for assignments in an engineering problems course completes the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type.
Index Terms
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Certificates, 1923-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cadet chevron patches, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Virginia Tech pennants, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Commemorative pins and reunion armbands, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Invitations and programs, 1920-1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Notes and ephemera, 1923-1924, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Printed materials, 1924-1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Alumni Association Century Club plaque, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1921-1924, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Problems in engineering - drawings, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 10)